I don't know this ceiling.
（ナツキ･スバル）知らない天井だ
The wound on my stomach?
お腹の傷―
Gone.
なーし
Everything considered, she must've done it.
状況から考えて あの子
エミリアの回復魔法かな
Emilia's healing power, huh?
Well, at any rate, I guess I escaped
having to Return by Death this time.
とにかく 何にせよ―
今回は 死に戻りは
回避できたってことだな
But wouldn't you normally wake up
to a girl asking, "Are you awake?"
にしても 普通目覚めたら
“起きた？” なーんて―
after she'd spent all night caring
for you by your bedside.
枕元で看病してくれてた美少女が
声をかけてくれるもんだろ？
It's kinda flawed for a story
about being summoned.
召喚ものとして
ちょっと不備が目立つぞ
A looping hallway, huh?
ループする廊下
I'll be stuck in it until I find
the correct room, right?
正解の部屋を見つけなきゃ
出れない的な展開か？
The tried-and-true pattern tells me it's probably behind the first door!
ありがちなパターンとしては
最初の部屋がゴールの可能性
I suppose you are one
profoundly aggravating man.
（ベアトリス）
なんて心の底から
腹立たしい奴なのかしら
First NPC found!
（スバル）第一村人発見
Your cute face is gonna go
to waste if you're that cold.
そんなツンツンしてると
かわいい顔が台無しだぜ
Come on, smile. Smile!
ほら スマイルスマイル
A derisive sneer is the only
"smile" worth giving you.
お前に見せる笑顔なんて
嘲笑で十分なのよ
Are you mad because
I guessed right on my first try?
ひょっとして 俺が一発で
正解引いたから怒ってるのか？
I've always been a pretty lucky guesser.
俺 昔っから
こういう引きが強くてさ
I totally understand why game masters
would want me in all the events,
ゲームマスターからしたら―
全部のイベント踏んでほしい
気持ちは分かるけどな
but too bad for you.
すまねえ すまねえ
So what is this place anyway?
で？ とりあえず
ここってどこよ？
It's Betty's multipurpose room.
I suppose it's both a library and a bedroom.
（ベアトリス）
フン ベティーの書庫兼
寝室兼用私室かしら
Talk about your token response.
額面通りの受け答え
今 はやりのマニュアル幼女か？
Are you one of those manual
girls everyone's into now?
Betty's had just about enough.
（ベアトリス）
そろそろベティーも限界なのよ
I suppose it's time to teach you a lesson.
ちょっと思い知らせてやろうかしら
Hey, what are you gonna do?
おい 何しでかす気だ？
Don't you dare move.
動くんじゃないのよ
Any last words?
（ベアトリス）
何か言いたいことでも？
D-Don't hurt me.
い… 痛くしないでね
What did you do to me, you drill loli!?
（スバル）
何しやがった ドリルロリ…
Not much. I suppose all I did
was collect the mana within your body.
ちょっと体の中のマナを
徴収しただけかしら
On the bright side,
I now know you're not an enemy.
まあ 敵意がないのは
確かめられたのよ
お前 人間じゃねえな
You're not human, are you?
And I'm not talking about your personality.
この場合 性格的な意味じゃなく
気づくのが遅いかしら
I suppose even you would notice eventually.
I take it back. Your personality isn't human either.
（スバル）
訂正 性格的にも人間じゃねえ
Do not measure a proud,
noble being by your standards, human.
（ベアトリス）
気高く尊き存在を
お前の尺度で測るんじゃないのよ
人間
I know this ceiling.
知ってる天井だ
Oh, he has awakened, Sister.
（レム）
あら 目覚めましたね 姉様
Indeed, he has awakened, Rem.
（ラム）
そうね 目覚めたわね レム
I, a denizen of the night, waking in the morning?
夜のけん属だった俺が
朝に起きるとか―
I'm getting all emotional.
胸が熱くなるなあ
I'd better go to sleep a second time.
ここはやはり二度寝…
ああ いや―
No, I woke up earlier,
so this'll be the third time.
さっき一度起きたから
三度寝としゃれ込むべきか
My, what a deadbeat thing to say.
（レム）
まあ 穀つぶしの発言ですよ
聞きました？ 姉様
Did you hear that, Sister?
Yes, truly a loser's words. I heard him, Rem.
（ラム）
ええ ろくでなしの発言ね
聞いたわよ レム
All right!
Who are these two voices that
keep criticizing me in stereo!?
さっきからステレオチックに
俺を責める 君ら誰よ？
N-No way.
バ… バカな
Maid uniforms are a thing in this world too?
この世にも メイド服が
存在するっていうのか
I've always imagined maids
as the living embodiment of elegance,
メイドは俺にとって 奥ゆかしさの
体現のイメージそのものだったが…
but I can live with this too!
これも悪くない！
How terrible. You are being
violated in our guest's mind, Sister.
（レム）
大変ですよ
今 お客様の頭の中で―
卑わいな辱めを受けています
姉様が
It is terrible. You are experiencing
the ultimate shame in our guest's mind, Rem.
大変だわ
今 お客様の頭の中で―
恥辱の限りを受けているのよ
レムが
Don't underestimate the power of my fantasies.
俺のキャパシティ ナメんなよ
２人まとめて妄想の餌食だぜ
You're both fair prey in them.
Can't you wake up more peacefully, Subaru?
（エミリア）
もっとおとなしく起きたり
できなかったの？
スバル
Whoever picked that outfit totally gets it!
（スバル）
この服 選んだ奴は分かってる！
I don't know what you're talking about,
何のことだか分からないけど―
but the fact I know it's something silly
is rather disappointing.
くだらないことって分かるのが
すごーく残念
Listen to this, Emilia-sama.
聞いてください エミリア様
My dear sister was just violated by that man.
あの方にひどい辱めを受けました
姉様が
Please listen to this, Emilia-sama.
聞いてちょうだい エミリア様
Rem was held prisoner and shamed by that man.
あの男に監禁凌辱されたのよ
レムが
Try not to tease him too much, okay?
あなたたちも あんまり
からかい過ぎないの
Very well, Emilia-sama.
My sister is very sorry.
はい エミリア様
姉様も反省しています
Very well, Emilia-sama.
Rem is very sorry as well.
はい エミリア様
レムも反省しているわ
Subaru, how's your body doing?
スバル 体の調子は大丈夫？
どこか変だったりしない？
Does anything feel off?
Huh? Oh, I'm just a little
groggy from oversleeping.
（スバル）
ん？ ああ
寝過ぎてちょっとだるいくらい
You healed me, didn't you, Emilia-tan?
助けてくれたのって
エミリアたんだよな？
Huh? "Tan"?
え？ “たん”？
What does "tan" imply?
“たん”って何？
Uh, just ignore it, okay?
そこはスルーの方向で
But seriously, thanks. I owe you one.
けど マジありがとう　助かった
No, I should be thanking you.
ううん お礼を言うのは私のほう
You barely know me,
yet you risked your life to save me.
ほとんど知らない私のことを
命がけで助けてくれたじゃない
Healing your wounds was the very least I could do.
ケガの治療なんて
当たり前なんだから
Okay, let's start this off right.
（スバル）
んじゃ 改めまして―
It's time to dive headfirst
into a brand new day!
新しい１日の始まりといきますか
This place is seriously huge.
やっぱり でけえな
The yard isn't so much a yard as a field.
庭も 庭ってより原っぱだ
Those are unusual movements.
What are you doing?
珍しい動きだけど 何してるの？
俺の故郷に伝わる
由緒正しい準備運動
An ancient practice of my homeland
called "warm-up exercises."
Come on, Emilia-tan! Together now!
さっ エミリアたんも ご一緒に
Radio calisthenics, number 2!
ラジオ体操第二―
Bounce on both feet to loosen up your body!
両足跳びで 軽く全身をほぐす運動
Huh? You're kidding! What is that?
え？ ウソ 何？
Just do what I do.
俺のマネしてやってみよう
I'll drill the essence of radio calisthenics into you!
ラジオ体操の神髄を
たたき込んじゃるぜ
Now, raise both arms and shout, "Victory!"
両手を掲げて―
ビクトリー！
V-Victory!
ビ… ビクトリー！
Victory!
（パック）ビクトリー！
ビクトリー！
Victory!
Hi, Subaru! Great morning, isn't it?
ああ おはようスバル
いい朝だね
Well, ever since the wee hours of the morning,
it hasn't exactly been smooth sailing for me.
俺にとっては 割と深夜から
朝にかけて波乱万丈だったけどな
Looping hallways and a little girl with a mean streak.
ループする廊下と
タチの悪い幼女の猛威
And of course, shedding the sweet sweat of passion with Emilia-tan!
そして エミリアたんと
一緒に流す 情熱の汗
Don't make it sound so scandalous!
人聞き悪い言い方しないの
Good morning, Puck.
おはよう パック
Sorry I pushed you so hard yesterday.
昨日はいろいろ
無理させてごめんね
Morning, Lia. I almost lost you yesterday.
おはよう リア
昨日は危うく
君を失うところだった
I can never thank Subaru enough.
スバルには
感謝してもし足りないくらい
I have to repay him somehow.
何か お礼をしなきゃ
Okay, then...
じゃあ―
Let me pet your fur whenever I want!
好きな時に
その毛並み触らせてくれ
Huh? That's all?
え？ そんなことでいいの？
For a connoisseur of fine fur like myself,
俺みたいな
一流の毛並み職人的には―
being able to dote on the object
of your affection anytime
触りたい愛玩対象を
いつでもめでられるってのは―
is worth as much as a multimillionaire's riches!
100万の富と引き換えにしても
惜しくない対価だぜー
Oh, man, these ears.
耳 ヤッバいな
I'm in love with how soft you are.
もう俺は お前の
フワフワっぷりにメロメロだわ
I can kind of read your mind,
so I know you feel that way,
うすぼんやり
心が読めるから分かるけど―
but I'm amazed you can actually say it!
本気て言ってるところがすごいね
It's okay, Lia.
平気だよ リア
（エミリア）あ…
I can't find a trace of malice,
hostility, or ill-intent in Subaru.
（パック）
スバルには 悪意とか敵意とか
害意ってものは見当たらない
It's so cute how you call her "Lia" too.
そのリアって呼び方 かわいいな
Not as cute as your "Emilia-tan"!
君のエミリアたんには負けるよ
You really are strange, Subaru.
ホントにスバルって不思議
Huh?
Oh? What brings you two here?
あれ ２人ともどうかしたの？
Emilia-sama.
（２人）エミリア様―
Our lord, Roswaal-sama, has returned.
当主 ロズワール様が
お戻りになられました
Please come inside.
どうか お屋敷へ
I was watching you from upstairs,
and you know what?
（ベアトリス）
上から見てた感じ あれなのよ―
I suppose you are as dumb as you look.
お前 相当に頭が残念みたいかしら
What's got you so high
and mighty, you damn loli!?
（スバル）
いきなり何を言いやがんだ
このロリ
I suppose that word means nothing good.
何かしら その単語
I have never heard it before,
but it irritates me somehow.
聞いたことないのに
不快な感覚だけはするのよ
Hey, Betty. It's been four days.
やあ ベティー ４日ぶり
Have you been nice and ladylike?
ちゃんと元気で
おしとやかにしてたかな？
にーちゃ！
Bubby!
I've been waiting for you to come home.
にーちゃの帰りを
心待ちにしてたのよ
Do you suppose you could
spend today with me?
今日は
一緒にいてくれるのかしら？
Sure, no problem.
うん 大丈夫だよ
Let's take the chance to relax together today.
久しぶりに
２人でゆっくりしようか
Yay!
（ベアトリス）わーいなのよ
フフッ おったまげたでしょ
In a dither, aren't you?
Beatrice is so taken with Puck.
ベアトリスが
パックにべったりだから
"In a dither"? Haven't heard that in awhile.
“おったまげた”って
きょうび聞かねえな
My, my! How unusual to see you here, Beatrice.
（ロズワール･Ｌ･メイザース）
おや？
ベアトリスがいるなんて珍しい
I'm so happy you've decided to dine with me.
久々に わーたしと食事を一緒に
してくれる気になったとは―
うれしいじゃーないの
I suppose that boy is more than
enough addle-brained fools for me.
頭 幸せなのは
そこの奴だけで十分かしら
Betty was only waiting for Bubby!
ベティーは
にーちゃを待ってただけなのよ
You guys hired a clown
to entertain you before each meal?
（スバル）
飯の前の余興に
いちいちピエロ雇ってんのか
I'll never understand how rich folks think.
金持ちの考えは分からねえな
Um, Subaru, that man is...
あの スバル その人は…
Oh, no. It's quite all right, Emilia-sama.
いやいやいやー
かまいませんよ エミリア様
What's that mean?
どういうこと？
Only that I am the lord of this
manor, Roswaal L. Mathers,
（ロズワール）
私が この屋敷の当主―
ロズワール･Ｌ･メイザース
というわーけだよ
Natsuki Subaru-kun.
ナツキ･スバルくん
This is way better than normal food!
普通以上にうめえな
（ロズワール）ンフー
She may not look it, but Rem
is quite the exceptional cook.
こう見えて レムの料理は
ちょっとしたものだよ
So this was cooked by the blue-haired one, um...
この料理は青髪の…
えっと レムちゃんでいいのか？
Rem-chan is fine, right?
You made this?
が 作ったの？
Yes, sir.
はい お客様
I do the cooking in this house.
当家の食卓は
レムが預かっています
My sister is not very good at cooking.
姉様は料理が
あまり得意ではないので
Oh, I see where this is going.
Twins who are good at different things?
ははーん 双子で得意スキルが
違うパターンだ
Is your sister good at cleaning, then?
じゃあ 姉様は
掃除が得意なかんじ？
Yes, that is correct.
はい そうです
My sister excels at housework,
particularly cleaning and laundry.
姉様は 掃除 洗濯を
家事の中では得意としています
So, Rem-rin, you're good at cooking,
but bad at cleaning and laundry?
じゃあ レムりんは
料理系得意だけど―
掃除と洗濯は苦手か
No, I am generally good at all household tasks.
いえ レムは基本的に
家事全般が得意です
I am also better at cleaning
and laundry than my sister.
掃除 洗濯も得意ですよ 姉様より
Why is your sister even here, then!?
（スバル）
姉様の存在意義 消えたな
You are truly a strange young man.
本当に不思議だーね 君
You visit the mansion of Margrave Mathers
in the Kingdom of Lugunica,
ルグニカ王国のメイザース辺境伯の
邸宅まで来て―
yet you claim total ignorance
of the state of affairs here!
なーんにも事情を知らないってー
言うんだから
"State of affairs here"?
Is something bad going down?
国の状況って…
何かマズいことになってんの？
Well, it's not exactly in an agreeable position.
穏当な状態ではないねえ
After all, Lugunica is currently without a king.
なーにせ 今のルグニカは
王が不在
Please, there's no need to be so concerned.
そーんな警戒しなくても
心配ご無用
Everyone is well aware of this reality.
すーでに市政にまで知れ渡った
厳然たる事実だーからね
Really?
さよけ
I expected a "now that you know our secret,
I can't let you leave alive" thing.
秘密を知られたからには―
生かして帰さん展開に
なるかと思ったぜ
Around the same time that the king passed,
（ロズワール）
王がお隠れになったのと
同時期に―
an epidemic struck the royal castle!
城内で
はやり病が まん延してねーえ
The king and his children were the last of his line.
王と その子孫は根絶やし
A council of wise men
currently manages the nation,
現状 国の運営は
賢人会によって行われ―
and they are now in the process
of selecting a new king!
新しい王の選出に向けて
動いているところなーんだよ
なるほど だんだん分かってきたぜ
I see. I'm starting to get the picture.
Besides the king's absence, the royal selection
is causing unrest in the kingdom.
王国は 王不在なうえに
王選出のドタバタで混乱中
Then, suddenly, I appear from another world—
そこへ現れる謎の異国人 俺…
Wait, I'm totally suspect here!
俺 超怪しいな
And on top of that,
さーらに付け加えちゃうと―
you made contact with Emilia-sama,
thus becoming connected to my household!
エミリア様に接触して―
我がメイザース家と
関係を持ったわけだーしね
ん？ 何で屋敷の主(あるじ)が
エミリアたんを 様付けで呼ぶ？
Wait, why is the lord of the mansion
calling her "Emilia-sama"?
It's only natural to address someone
of higher status with all due respect.
当然のこーとだよ
自分より地位の高い方を
敬称で呼ぶのはねーえ
えっと…
エミリアたんてば つまり…
Um, so Emilia-tan would be...
Right now, I'm a candidate
今の私の肩書きは―
to become the forty-second ruler
of the Kingdom of Lugunica.
ルグニカ王国 42代目の
王候補の１人
Margrave Roswaal is acting as my sponsor.
そこのロズワール辺境伯の
後ろ盾でね
What!?
Sorry to surprise you.
驚かせちゃってごめんね
I wasn't trying to keep it a secret.
こんなに黙ってるつもりなんて
なかったんだけど
Hey, it's that insignia.
（スバル）
あの徽章(きしょう)じゃねえか
This qualifies one as a candidate for king.
これは 王選参加者の資格
It's a touchstone for determining
if one is worthy of the throne.
ルグニカ王国の王座に座るのに
ふさわしい人物かどうか―
それを確かめる 試金石なの
Wait, Emilia-tan, you lost an insignia
that qualifies you to rule an entire kingdom?
てことは エミリアたん―
王選参加資格の徽章を
なくしてたのか？
Don't put it like that! I didn't lose it!
なくしたなんて 人聞きの悪い
手癖の悪い子に盗られちゃったの
A thief stole it from me!
That's the same thing!
一緒だ！
And what happens if you lose that thing anyway?
っていうか マジでそれ
なくすとどうなっちゃうの？
Will some government body issue you another?
役所で 再発行とかできんの？
Oh, my! If you lost it,
then all doubts would be cleared.
（ロズワール）
まあー なくしました
じゃ済まないのは―
間違いないだろうねーえー
The passing thought that someone
who cannot protect a tiny insignia
小さな徽章１つ
守りきれない人間に―
is unfit to rule an entire nation
would spell the end of it.
国を任せられないって思われれば
それで おーしまい
Now that I think about it,
I did a damn good job.
改めて考えると
俺 超グッジョブ
This totally raises my expectations for a reward.
これはもう
ご褒美に期待が高まっちゃうな
Yeah, you're right.
うん そうなの
スバルは私にとって すごく恩人
You helped me more than you could ever imagine.
So ask for anything.
だから何でも言って
Merely say the word.
褒美は思いのまま
さあー 何でも望みを言いたまーえ
You may have anything your heart desires!
（スバル）フッフフ…
だったら 俺の願いは１つだ
In that case, I have but one request.
Hire me to work in this mansion!
俺を この屋敷で
雇ってくれ！
Achoo.
（ラム）へくち
（エミリア）
それじゃ ちょっとあんまり…
That isn't quite right.
ほかに合うのなかったの？ スバル
Wasn't there anything else that fit you, Subaru?
Oddly, some of the girls' stuff fit me, but...
（スバル）
女物なら なぜかあったんだが
申し訳ありません お客様
改めスバルくん
Our deepest apologies, sir. I mean, Subaru-kun.
無様ですね お客様
改めバルス
You look quite ridiculous, sir. I mean, Balse.
Hey, older sister, you just turned
my name into a blinding curse.
（スバル）
おい姉様 俺の名前が
目潰しの呪文になってんぞ
Rem, looking at Balse's ridiculous
appearance, do you notice anything?
レム 無様なバルスの姿を見て
気づくことは？
The shoulders don't fit right,
his legs are short, and his eyes are scary?
肩周りがおかしいのと―
足が短いことと
目つきが怖いことですか？
どうにもならない部分が
２か所入ってきたな！
I have no control over two of those things!
（ラム）
こんな貧相な格好で
働かせておくなんてできないわ
We cannot allow you to work here
in such shady-looking attire.
ロズワール様の
品位が疑われるから
It would bring question
to Roswaal-sama's dignity.
Let us alter the jacket, at least.
上着だけでも
直してしまいましょう
Rem, if you please.
レム お願い
All right, I have to study
for the royal selection.
それじゃ
私は王政の勉強があるから―
Good luck with your work, Subaru.
スバルもお仕事頑張ってね
Yep, leave it to me, Emilia-tan.
おう 任せろエミリアたん
I shall take your measurements.
Stand still and keep your back straight.
採寸します　そこに
背筋を伸ばして立ってください
あまり変な声を
出さないでください
Please refrain from strange noises. It's unpleasant.
不愉快ですふ
That was beyond my control!
今のは不可抗力だろ
This tickles a guy in all kinds of ways!
いろいろと こそばゆくて
男の子は大変なんだよ
This is the VIP room.
（ラム）ここが貴賓室
This is the bathing room.
ここが浴室
This is the kitchen.
ここが厨(ちゅう)房
And this is the lavatory.
そして ここがお手洗い
In a mansion like this,
the restroom must be huge.
（スバル）
これだけの豪邸
トイレもさぞかしでかいんだろうな
You're the best, Bubby!
Your fur feels like heave—
にーちゃステキ
最高の毛並みなのよ
誰にも言わないから 安心しろ
人はみんな その感触の前では…
Don't worry. I won't tell a soul.
The feel of that fur would make anyone—
Hey! Let me finish!
…って 最後まで聞けよ！
これがベアトリス様の扉渡り
That was Beatrice-sama's Door Crossing.
So it's a spell that can connect
any door in the mansion to her room?
つまり 屋敷の扉のどことでも
自室につなげられる魔法ってことか
Once Beatrice-sama has eliminated her presence,
一度 ベアトリス様が
気配を消されたら―
屋敷の扉を総当たりしないかぎり
見つからないわ
the only way to find her is
to try every door in the mansion.
（スバル）ここだ
She's in here!
That was impressive, Subaru.
すごいね スバル
You picked the right door again?
また正解を引きやがったのよ
What did I tell you?
言っただろ
I'm a flag-crusher who makes game masters cry.
俺は ゲームマスター泣かせの
フラグクラッシャーだ
（ベアトリス）
言ってる意味が分からないのよ！
I don't understand what you're saying!
And I don't even know who you are.
（スバル）
俺もお前が誰だか分からねえよ
ロズっちの妹？
Roscchi's little sister?
I suppose I'd rather die than be his sister!
あれの妹なんて
願い下げかしら フン
Betty is the librarian who oversees the
Roswaal mansion's forbidden library.
ベティーは ロズワールの
お屋敷にある禁書庫の司書さんだよ
Roswaal-sama is the greatest
magic-user in the kingdom.
（ラム）
ロズワール様は
王国 最高の魔術師
He has many books that
must not be seen by others.
人目に触れさせられない本も
たくさんあります
ベアトリス様は契約で
それを守ってらっしゃるのです
Beatrice-sama is contracted to protect them.
Now that you know, go away.
分かったら さっさと消えるのよ
This concludes our tour of the mansion.
（ラム）
屋敷全体の案内は
これでおしまいね
Any questions?
ここまでで質問は？
I know there's no point
in saying this now that it's over,
終わってから言うのも
なんだけど―
but shouldn't Emilia-tan be
my guide for the tour event?
案内イベントって 本来なら―
エミリアたんが やってくれるべき
イベントな気がしないかな…
If you have no questions,
let us get to your actual job.
（ラム）
ないようだから―
実際の仕事のほうに
移るとしましょうか
You will help me with my work, Balse.
ラムの仕事を
バルスにも手伝ってもらうわ
This must be where my hidden skill as a butler comes to light!
ここで俺の秘められた
執事スキルが覚醒する展開
Today's work includes tending to the front yard
and garden, helping to prepare lunch,
（ラム）
今日のラムの仕事は
前庭と庭園の手入れ―
昼食の準備を手伝って その後
銀食器を磨き 寝台の布団干し―
polishing the silver, airing the futons,
doing the laundry, cleaning the bathroom,
洗濯と浴室の掃除
月に一度の 屋敷全体のすす払い…
and completing the mansion's
monthly soot cleaning.
ああ 疲れた
I'm exhausted...
（レム）
レムです
スバルくん 今 いいですか
This is Rem.
Do you have a moment, Subaru-kun?
Sure, I'm good!
ああ 大丈夫 大丈夫
I won't do anything weird, so come on in.
変なこととかしてないから
入っていいぜ
（レム）
かえって信ぴょう性の
薄れる許可ですね
The phrasing of your permission
makes you sound less credible.
失礼します
Pardon me, then.
ひょっとして もうできたのか？
You already finished it?
While Roswaal-sama's clothing
requires the utmost care,
ロズワール様の衣装だったら
丁寧さを優先ですけど―
since this is yours...
スバルくんのでしたので
Did you just imply that you cut corners?
（スバル）
今 言外に手抜き宣言した？
I hate to admit it, but it's perfect.
悔しいけど完璧
どうよ 似合う？
Well? Do I look good?
（レム）
その灰色の服の珍しさと
合わせて―
Combined with those unusual gray clothes of yours,
珍奇な格好をさせたら
右に出る者はいませんね
no one in any kind of strange
garment could rival you.
（スバル）
よーし 褒めてねえな
Okay! Not a compliment at all!
What shall we do about those?
（レム）
裾のほうはどうしますか？
（スバル）
こっちは簡単だ
針と糸はあるか？
This one's easy. Got a needle and thread?
I have both on me. Shall I repair them now?
持ってきています
今 やってしまいましょうか？
Nah, I'll do it.
いや 自分でやるよ
俺の裁縫スキルを侮るなよ
Don't look down on my sewing skills.
驚きました
I am surprised.
裁縫に関しては 満点です
I must say your sewing earns full marks.
ただ スバルくん自身と同じで
あまり使いどころがありませんけど
Very much like you, however,
I fail to see how that's useful.
（スバル）あたーっ！
Ow!
You may get full marks for sewing,
but you are still useless with a knife, Balse.
裁縫は満点でも
包丁使いはまるでダメね バルス
Such a lovely picture could be painted
of you peeling vegetables, Sister.
さすが 姉様は
野菜の皮むきする姿も絵になります
Your bias is so blatant it's almost comforting!
すがすがしいまでの身内びいきだな
I'd like a comment on my work too!
俺の仕事ぶりにも
コメントが欲しいです
I pity the farmer who grew those vegetables.
（レム）
そのお野菜を作った
畑の持ち主がかわいそうです
Stop! You're breaking my heart!
心が痛いからやめて
You do not know how to handle a knife, Balse.
バルスは
ナイフの扱いがなってないのよ
You should hold the knife still,
turning the vegetable.
ナイフは固定して
野菜のほうを回すのよ
何を隠そう
ラムの得意料理は蒸(ふ)かし芋よ
Frankly speaking, my best dish is steamed tatoes.
勝ち誇った顔で
何を言いだしてんだよ
Why do you look so proud of that!?
クソ 見てろ
俺の愛刀 流れ星が―
Just watch me, damn it!
My favorite blade, Shooting Star,
will show you a thing or two—
お前に目に物
見せてくれちゃるぜ
It sliced right through me!
サックリ持ってかれたー
It's been five days since
Subaru-kun came to the mansion.
（ロズワール）
その後のスバルくんの様子は
どんなもんだい？
屋敷に来て ５日―
How has he been?
By now, we should be seeing something.
そろそろ 見えてくるものが
あるころじゃーないかね？
（ラム）
料理 洗濯 掃除
どれを取っても まるでダメです
Cooking, laundry, cleaning.
He is incompetent at all of them.
（ロズワール）手厳しーいね
How strict of you.
それで 間者の可能性はどうかな？
And?
What of the potential he is a spy?
I cannot deny it exists,
but I believe the possibility is slim.
否定はできませんが
その可能性はかなり低いと思います
良くも悪くも… というか
特に悪い意味で目立ち過ぎです
For better or worse.
Specifically for worse, he is too conspicuous.
あまり目立ち過ぎると―
And if he's too conspicuous...
…ってなことにも
なりかねないってのに―
Despite that possibility, he certainly is carefree.
のんきなもんだよね
As I personally see it,
interfering would be wise.
私の立場としては
ジャマするべきなんだろうけどねえ
They are only children.
（ラム）
どちらも子供ですから
放っておいても 何も起きませんよ
Even if we leave them be,
nothing will happen.
It can't be all that fun to watch me.
（エミリア）
見てても楽しいもの
じゃないでしょう？
Nothing is boring when
I'm with you, Emilia-tan.
エミリアたんと一緒にいて
退屈と思うこととかねえよ
That makes me happy, even if it's just flattery.
そう言われると
お世辞でもうれしい
Besides, we haven't had a lot of chances
to talk in the past few days.
それに ほら―
ここ何日かは
ゆっくり話す機会もなかったじゃん
I guess so.
（エミリア）そうよね
スバルは お屋敷の仕事を
覚えるのに大変だっただろうし
You must be having a hard time getting used to your work here.
Hell yeah, I am! It's killing me!
超大変 マジ苦しい
I wanna rest my head in your arms,
on your chest, and then on your lap.
エミリアたんに
腕と胸とひざを借りて―
ローテーションで癒されたい
はいはい そうやって
ちゃかせる間は 大丈夫そうね
Yeah, yeah.
If you can joke around
like that, you must be fine.
The moon sure is pretty.
月がきれいですね
手が届かない所にあるもんね
True beauty is always beyond our reach.
（スバル）
狙って言ったわけじゃ
なかったのに―
I got a really touching response
without even trying to!
すごい心にくる
コメントが返ってきた
On another note, don't you
think you're too unambitious?
だけど スバルって
ちょっと欲がなさすぎない？
パックの時もだし―
Like earlier with Puck,
or when you asked for my
name back in the capital.
王都で 私の名前を聞いた時だって
You just don't get it, Emilia-tan.
エミリアたんは分かってねえな
I want what I want at that exact moment,
俺は本気の本気で
心の底から―
and I want it from the bottom of my heart.
その時 その時の
本当に欲しいもんを望んでるんだぜ
Huh?
あの時
俺は君の名前が知りたかった
At the time, I wanted to know your name.
In a new land, nervous and unsure of the future, I had no expectations for tomorrow.
明日の見通しも立ってなくて
新天地で不安でテンパってて
Looking back on it calmly,
たぶん 落ち着いて考えたら―
I'm sure there were other
things I should have wanted.
欲しがらなきゃいけないものも
ほかにいろいろとあったんだと思う
でも 俺は自分に
ウソはつかない男だ
But I can't lie to myself.
ロズっちへの頼みも同じさ
Same thing with the request I made to Roscchi.
俺ってば 今 徹頭徹尾の一文無し
I'm flat broke right now.
I could cheat him out of a fortune and live it up,
大金せしめて
豪遊ってのも手だけど―
継続的な生活基盤を
手に入れるってのも手でしょ
but I can just as easily obtain
a source of livelihood, right?
（エミリア）
別にそれなら
使用人じゃなくても―
In that case, couldn't you have become
a permanent guest, rather than an employee?
食客扱いとかで
よかったんじゃない？
I never thought of that!
その手があったか！
お… おおっとやべえ
かっちょ悪(わり)い
Oh, man, talk about pathetic.
努力は秘めるもんだよね
Your efforts should be kept a secret, right?
（エミリア）
治癒魔法 かけてあげようか？
Do you want me to use my healing magic?
Nah, I'm fine like this.
（スバル）
いや いいよ このままで
どうして？
Why?
なんか言葉にしにくいんだけど―
It's kind of hard to explain, but...
I guess it's kind of like
proof of the effort I put in.
そうだな これは俺の
努力した証だから
I don't actually dislike
exerting myself, you know.
俺って 意外と努力
嫌いじゃねんだよ
Learning to do something
I couldn't do before is, well...
できないことが
できるようになんのって―
なんつーか… 悪くない
It's not such a bad feeling.
そうよね
I guess that's true.
Yeah, I think you're right.
うん そうだと思う
はあ もう スバルのバカ
You're such a silly man.
Hey, now. I don't know about that reaction.
あれあれ
リアクションおかしくねえ？
You're supposed to fall for me all over again.
ほれ直してもいいとこだよ ここ
"Again"? There was no first time.
もともと ほれてません
もう バカなんだから
Honestly, you're so silly.
EMA...
ＥＭＴ…
エミリアたん マジ 天使の略
It's short for "Emilia-tan, mesmerizing angel."
感謝してるのに
またそうやってちゃかす
I'm praising you, and you're
fooling around again!
Anyway, I know you're working hard,
それにしても
頑張ってるのは分かるけど―
but how did your hands get so torn up?
どうやったら
そんなに手がボロボロになるの？
I cut this one up with a knife in the kitchen.
厨房でナイフで切ったり―
And this happened the evening that I went shopping in town.
あと こっちは夕方
村に買い物に行った時―
A little animal some kids
were playing with bit me.
子供たちが戯れてた小動物に
超ガブられた
It wasn't the result of your effort?
努力の成果じゃなかったの？
Those kids were ruthless.
（スバル）
村のガキども 容赦なく
たたくわ 蹴るわ―
They hit me, kicked me, and wiped their
runny noses on me. It was seriously the worst.
鼻水拭くわで
最悪だったぜ チクショウ
小さい子の面倒見とか
よさそうだもんね スバル
I can see you being good
with small children, Subaru.
そうだ よかったら明日とか―
I know!
Wanna come with me tomorrow
to get revenge on those ki—
俺と一緒に
村のガキどもにリベンジ…
もとい 小動物の見学に行かねえ？
I mean, to watch the small animal?
スバルと一緒に行くの
イヤじゃないけど…
I'm not really against the idea, but...
Then let's go.
じゃあ 行こうぜ
It might cause you trouble if we're seen together.
でも 私が一緒だと―
スバルの迷惑に
なるかもしれなくて…
Okay, got it! Let's go!
よし分かった 行こうぜ
Are you listening to me?
ちゃんと聞いてくれてる？
I am! I hang on every word you say, Emilia-tan!
聞いてるよ
俺がエミリアたんの一言一句
聞き逃すわけないじゃん
もう…
Jeez...
私の勉強が 一段落して―
Only after you finish all your work,
and I have a break from my studies, okay?
ちゃんとスバルのお仕事が
終わってからだからね
よっしゃー！ ラジャッター！
All right! Roger that!
Hey, loli girl! You're still up?
ヘーイ ロリっ子
まだ起きてんのか？
当たり前のように 扉渡りを
破るようになりやがったかしら
I suppose you can break through my
Door Crossing like it's nothing now.
Now, now. I just wanted
to say hello before I went to bed.
まあ 寝る前に
挨拶しようと思っただけだ
Can I try that too?
俺もそれやっていい？
I suppose only Bubby is permitted to touch me.
（ベアトリス）
ベティーに触れていいのは
にーちゃだけかしら
No fair keeping all the fun to yourself.
自分だけ楽しんでずりい
Well, I'm in a good mood, so I can let it go—
まあ 俺は今
機嫌がいいから…
Enough! Get out of here!
（ベアトリス）
もういいから消えるのよ
ベティーには
関係のないことかしら
I suppose Betty doesn't have any part in that.
All right, so for our date tomorrow,
（スバル）
明日のデートは
村まで行って―
I'll have to come up with an excuse
to ditch those kids at the village.
適当に理由作って
ガキども まかなきゃな
Oh, but first, I've gotta learn where all
the good views and flower fields and stuff are.
おっと その前に
見晴らしのいい場所とか―
花畑の位置とか
リサーチしとかねえと
Crap! I can't sleep while I'm thinking about this!
やべえ
考えてると眠れねえ
あっ そうだ
Oh, I know!
パックが１匹
パックが２匹…
One Puck...
Two Pucks...
A hundred and one Pucks...
パックが101匹…
新しい朝がきた！ 希望の朝だ！
A new dawn has come! A dawn of hope!
ナツキ･スバル―
Natsuki Subaru will make giant strides today...
今日 飛躍の時を迎えます
What!? You were in here?
なな… 何だよ
いたのかよ
I'm so embarrassed!
恥ずかしいじゃねえか
声かけろよ！
You should have said something!
姉様 姉様―
Sister, Sister.
Our guest appears to be a bit confused.
どうやら少し
混乱されているみたいです お客様
レム レム―
Rem, Rem.
It appears our guest has gone crazy.
何やら 頭が
おかしくなってるみたいね お客様
Why are you calling me a guest?
いや お客様って… ハハ
You two and your jokes.
２人とも 冗談きつい…
（スバル）傷が…
The wounds...
Family Mansion
The   Happy Roswaal
ない
Family Mansion
The   Happy Roswaal
are gone.
Family Mansion
The   Happy Roswaal